Yara Gagen-Torn

Full Stack Software Developer

Valid Visa to work in New Zealand yaragagen@gmail.com 0223053540

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yara-gagen-torn/

Github: https://github.com/yara-gagentorn

Portfolio and Blog: https://yara-gagentorn.github.io/

About Me

Kia ora! I am a web developer, who also can dance. I bring with me life experience in multiple areas and huge passion for software developing to my new career in tech. Even though I've changed my life path from tech more than 10 years ago, I've always been a tech person, who is constantly admiring technologies and loves to solve problems more than anything else. Recently I have been developing a website for my hobby and I realised that I wanted to go back to tech. Experience which I've got during the bootcamp in Dev Academy has shown me that I am on the right track. I've enjoyed every aspect of the bootcamp - coding, working in teams, learning new technologies, solving all kinds of problems - and I want to learn more and apply my knowledge to solve real-world problems.

Skills/Technology

- JavaScript understanding of main concepts of JavaScript and use it for creating web applications and games
- React 800 hours learning and applying front end development principles
- Django framework currently there are two deployed projects based on Django framework created for my hobby
- Python basic understanding of the language, using Python in Django environment
- CMS (Joomla, Wordpress) experience of creating and supporting websites based on CMS
- Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Premier, Corel Draw

Experience

Countdown Supermarket
October 2022 - current Nightfill Assistance

Dev Academy Aotearoa

June - October 2022 Student / Apprentice - Software Development Bootcamp

- completed a 15 week full immersion software development bootcamp that mimics a
 real-life development team as closely as possible. The course taught us a modern
 web dev stack with a strong emphasis on human skills, empathy, collaboration, and
 working in teams using agile methodology. This experience inspired me and now I
 want to use everything I've learned to solve real life problems.
- Here are some of my projects which I've completed during the bootcamp: https://yara-gagentorn.github.io/projects/projects-content.html

Sentinel Apartment Building, Takapuna, Auckland

October 2021 - December 2022 Concierge

- provided exceptional service to residents of the luxury apartment building by answering questions and assisting with various requests
- managed complaints both in person and by phone
- performed general office duties
- solved basic tech problems

Salsa on Browns Bay, Auckland

November 2019 - current Party organiser

- organising free social dance parties for the local community
- work with a community centre, coordinate teachers, djs, photographers
- advertise and promote the event on facebook

Navigator, Russia (remote)

2014 - 2018 **Data Collector**

- monitoring, collection, organisation and interpretation of news for certain topics
- making regular reports for clients (in Russian language)

Education

1990 – 1998 School №411, Petergof, St. Petersburg, Russia

1998 – 2000 School №618, St. Petersburg, Russia

2000 – 2007 St. Petersburg State University (mathematics and mechanics faculty), St.

Petersburg, Russia

Qualification: information scientist majoring in "Applied informatics (in sociology)"

2018 – 2019 Whitecliffe Computer Power Plus, New Zealand Diploma in Software

Development (L6)

Mar–Nov 2021 Te Wananga o Aotearoa, New Zealand, Certificate in Small Business and Project Management (L4)

Jun-Oct 2022 Dev Academy, New Zealand, Qualification: Full-stack developer

Volunteer

Digital Seniors, Auckland

Dec 2022 - current Coach

 assisting seniors with various technology-related tasks, such as setting up and troubleshooting their smartphones and computers

Hobbies & Interests

Dancing, design and crafting, weight lifting, psychology.

References Available on Request